This is our land.
这是我们的土地.
A land of peace and of plenty.
一块资源丰富,和平的土地.
A land of harmony and hope.
一块充满希望,融洽的土地.
This is our land.
这是我们的土地.
Oceania.
大洋洲.
These are our people.
这是我们的人民.
The workers, the strivers, the builders.
那默默无闻的工人,那废寝忘食的拚搏者, 那奋斗不息的建设者.
The builders of our world, struggling...
我们心灵深处的脊梁, 在不断的奋斗...
fighting, bleeding...
在战斗, 在流血...
dying.
在牺牲.
On the streets of our cities and on the far-flung battlefields.
在我们城市的街道上,在遥远的战场上
Fighting against the mutilation of our hopes and dreams.
对抗着摧毁我们希望和梦想的敌人
Who are they?
他们是谁?
Eurasia! Eurasia!
欧亚大陆! 欧亚大陆!
They are the dark armies.
他们是无知的军队.
The dark, murdering armies of Eurasia.
无知,扼杀着欧亚大陆的军队
In the barren deserts of Africa and India...
在非洲和印度的死亡沙漠...
on the oceans of Australasia...
在澳大利亚海洋...
courage, strength, and youth are sacrificed.
勇气,力量,还有年青人无私奉献出自已的生命
Sacrificed to barbarians, whose only honor is atrocity.
牺牲在那些只崇尚暴行的野蛮人刀下.
But even as we grasp at victory...
但是,正当我们要庆祝胜利的时候...
there is a cancer, an evil tumor...
有一个瘤, 一个邪恶的毒瘤...
growing, spreading in our midst.
正在不停地生长, 逐渐在我们中间蔓延.
Shout, shout...
喊,喊...
shout out his name!
喊出他的名字!
Goldstein!
戈德斯坦!
Nothing the Party says is true.
党说的话没有一句是真的.
Nothing the Party does is good.
党干的事没有一样是好的...
Even the war itself isn't real.
甚至战争本身都不是真实的.
The Party wants you to believe we are at war...
党想要你们相信我们正处于战争中...
so as to channel your aggressions away from their rightful target...
从而想把你们愤怒的锋芒带离 他们阴谋的歇息的天堂.
the Party.
这就是党的本质.
Big Brother is not real.
老大哥不是现实的化身.
He is pure fiction, created by the Party.
他纯粹是虚构体,是被这个党虚造出来的.
The real rulers of the State...
国家的真正的统治者...
are unknown, faceless manipulators...
是那些不知名的,从不露面的幕后操作者...
who, because they are not known...
因为他们不为人们所知...他们
are able to wield power without let or hindrance.
能不受任何阻挡地行使权力.
People of Oceania, you are being duped.
大洋洲的人民,你们正在被愚弄...
The Party doesn't serve the people, it serves itself.
党不会为人民服务,它只会为自己服务.
We are not at war with Eurasia.
我们不会与欧亚大陆交战.
Death! Death! Traitor!
去死! 去死! 叛徒!
You are being made into obedient...
你们正在被转变成为一个个
stupid slaves of the Party.
温顺,愚蠢的党的奴隶.
Open your eyes.
睁开你们的眼睛.
See the evil that is happening to you.
看吧,邪恶阴影正烙在你们的身上.
The Party drops bombs on its own citizens.
党只会在它自己的市民中投下了炸弹.
Traitor!
判徒!
It is the Party, not the Eurasians, who are our enemies.
这个党就是我们的敌人,而不是 那些欧亚人.
Rise up.
站起来!
Throw off the yoke.
把那奴役的枷锁扔掉.
You have nothing to lose, and everything to gain.
你们已经走到路的尽头了!该是 站起来,重新赢得一切的时候了!
People of Oceania.
大洋洲的人民.
Big, Big, Big....
大, 大, 大...
Innuendo, deleted.
暗讽的话,不要说.
Intransigence, rendered as crime.
不让步,就是犯罪.
Inversion....
颠倒是非...
Back, Day One.
向后一天.
Ref. Times 14-2-84, Page 3, Byline 2, should read:
参考:时报.84年2月14日,页面3, 标题署名行二,内容为:
"Miniprod Forecasts lncrease Chocolate Ration, April, 1984...
"麦尼U罗德的预测增加了1984年 4月份的巧克力配给量...
"from 20 to 25 Grams Per Week."
"每周20-25克."
I confess to spreading the rumor, on orders from Goldstein...
我承认我是受命于戈德斯坦 而散布了这一谣传的...
that the war is not really with Eurasia, but with Eastasia.
---这场战争并不是真的与欧亚 大陆作战，而是与东亚。
That, for years, in fact since the days of our glorious Revolution...
多年来,可以说自从我们光荣 的革命日子开始...
I had no faith in our future.
我从来没有对我们的将来 抱有任何希望.
I forged government announcements and falsified figures...
我伪造了政府的公文...
quoted for agricultural and industrial production.
对农业和工业产值弄虚作假.
As a result of mental disturbance from my experiences during the atomic wars...
由于在原子战争时期我 的精神发生错乱...
I was a willing subject of Goldstein's influence.
我心甘情愿地成为了戈德斯坦 手中的一只棋子.
I was stubborn and egocentric.
我是顽固的,也是自私的.
When ownlife thoughts occurred to me, I reveled in them.
当本能意愿在我脑中形成的 时候,我便情不自禁地欢呼自我了.
I went into the proletarian zones...
我走到贫民的群体中去...
I had sex with prostitutes, I deliberately contracted syphilis.
我和妓女发生了关系,还故意 染上了梅毒.
It was at this time that I made contact with the Resistance.
就在这个时候,我开始接触 那些反叛者.
I was personally contacted by the archtraitor, Goldstein...
我还单独地被那个反叛头头 戈德斯坦引见...
and ordered to assassinate certain Inner Party officials.
然后命令我去暗杀党 内部的某些官员.
Bugger!
做奸者!
This I did.
这就是我的所做所为.
My agents forged documents and gained entry into the Ministry....
我的助手伪造公文,然后 混进了机要部门...
"Thoughtcrime is death.
"思想罪就是死罪.
"Thoughtcrime does not entail death.
思想罪不是死罪原由.
"I have committed, even before setting pen to paper...
即使在我动笔写以前 我已经犯下了...
"the essential crime that contains all others in itself. "
那种最可怕的罪行. 这是一个综合型的罪行.
I have spent many hours of my free time, encouraging my agents...
我已经花了我很多的空闲 时间,鼓励我的助手们...
to deface Party posters and hoarding announcements.
去故意损化党的宣传海报 和张贴的公文.
I read and memorized Goldstein's book.
我饱读并铭记戈德斯坦的著作.
For 30 years, I have plotted to bring down the Party.
30年来,我一直在密谋要推翻党.
I was sick in mind and body.
我在心理和身体上都有病态.
Together with my colleagues, Aaronson and Rutherford...
还有我的同伴,艾伦孙和卢瑟福...
I did counterfeit important Party documents...
我伪造了大量的党文件和证件...
including ex-London permits and travel passes.
包括出入伦敦的通行证和旅行护照.
And that by use of these documents...
利用这些证件...
my agents traveled freely throughout Airstrip One...
我的助手们可以在整个 飞机跑道一自由地行动...
encouraging insurrection and organizing a massive counterplot...
大力鼓吹反抗性,并且建立了 一个有效的反抗组织...
to destroy the innermost faction of the Oceanian leadership.
去摧毁大洋洲最核心的 领导层.
Furthermore...
此外...
I used my position of privilege within the Inner Party...
我利用在内部党内的职务之便...
to pervert and betray the truth at all times...
不断地背叛和扭曲事实...
and to suggest, wherever possible, that our traditional allies in Eastasia...
并向外界表明,无论什么时候,我们 在东亚的盟友...
were in fact, our deadly enemies.
实际上却是我们的死敌.
"April the 4th, 1984. "
"1984年4月4日. "
In my position as Chief Factory Planner...
作为工厂的主要策划者...
"I think... "
"我认为... "
I stole military plans...
我窃取了军事战略计划...
and, at vast financial profit, sold them to the Eurasian leadership.
然后以高价卖给欧亚国的领导们.
"... to the past...
"... 到过去...
"or to the future...
"到将来...
"to an age when thought is free.
"到一个思想解放的年代.
"From the age of Big Brother...
"从老大哥开始的年代...
"from the age of the Thought Police...
"从思想警察的年代...
"from a dead man...
"从一个死去的人...
"greetings!"
"致敬!"
30-to-40 group, take your places, please.
三十到四十岁的组员,请找 好自己的位置.
Right, let's see which one of us can touch his toes.
好的,让我们试一下看谁能够 到自己的脚趾.
Right over from the hips, brothers and sisters, please.
兄弟姐妹们,请从腰部往下弯.
One, two.
一,二.
Smith? 6079, Smith, W.?
史密斯?号码为6079的温斯顿.史密斯?
Yes, you.
对,就是你.
Bend lower.
给我弯低点.
You're not trying. Watch me.
你没有在认真做.看看我怎样做.
There, brother. That's what I want.
对了,兄弟.这样就对了.
Anyone under 45 is perfectly capable of touching his toes.
45岁以下的人是完全能够得到脚趾的.
I'm 39, and I've had four children.
我39岁了,还有4个孩子.
We don't all have the privilege of fighting in the front line.
我们不都是有机会到前线去战斗.
Remember our boys on the Malabar Front.
想想我们在马拉巴尔海岸前线的兄弟们.
Just think what they have to put up with.
想想他们正忍受着什么.
Production of water-heaters is up 1. 5 percent.
水加热产品产量上升了1.5%.
Switchgear, 4. 5 percent.
接电设备,4.5%.
Electrical wiring, 10 percent.
电线,10%.
Cigarettes, 18 percent.
香烟,18%.
Bricks, 3 percent.
砖块,3%.
Morning, Smith.
早上好,史密斯。
Parsons.
早上好,帕森斯.
Heard the rumor?
听到那个谣言了吗?
No. Good news, is it?
不.是个好消息,对吗?
I should say so, yes.
我觉得是个好消息.
Choco rations going up.
巧克力的供应量在增加.
Really?
真的吗?
Twenty-five grams next week.
下个星期25克.
Doubleplus good.
好极了.
Speakwrites, 14 percent.
述写器(Speakwrites) 14%.
Vibra-aging castings, 9 percent.
振动老化铸件 9%.
By the way, Smith, I seem to have run out of razor blades for some reason.
顺便说一下,史密斯,我的 剃刀刀片好像用完了.
You wouldn't happen to have any spare, would you?
你那里有没有多余的,嗯？
I'm sorry, brother. I'm on the last one.
对不起,兄弟.我现在用的已 经是最后一个了.
Bandages, 9 percent.
绷带，9%。
In 1983, Oceania's coal output...
在1983年，大洋洲的煤出口...
reached 630 million tons.
达到了6点三亿吨。
In 1976, coal output was 605 million tons...
而在1976年，煤出口仅为是 6点零五亿吨...
an increase of 4. 1 percent.
增长了4.1%。
5. 3 million tractors were produced...
拖拉机生产了5百3十万台...
an increase of 17. 6 percent.
增长了17.6%。
6. 1 million trucks...
卡车610万辆...
I wanted to ask you if you've got any razor blades?
我想问你找到刀片了吗?
I've tried all over the place.
我在所有的地方都找过了。
I've been using the same one for six weeks.
我一直用这个都六个星期了.
...a staggering increase of 93.4 percent.
一个令人诧目的93.4%增长.
Did you see the prisoners hanged yesterday?
你昨天去亲眼目睹那些 囚犯被掉死的场景吗?
No, I was working. But I shall see it on the screens.
没有,我当时在工作. 但是我可以在荧屏上看.
You'll pick up the gin on the way?
你想待会儿买酒吗?
I'll have two.
我要两瓶.
2.9 million Airstrip One Mark 5 submachine guns...
290万支马克5系列冲锋枪.
3. 1 million Grenville gas-operated light machine guns...
310万支格瑞威气动式自动轻机枪.
Give me a gin.
给我一瓶酒.
2.2 million.5 Victory recoil-operated heavy machine guns...
220万支胜利5系列后座力重型机枪...
6 million rifle grenades...
600万个枪榴弹...
9 million Perry pineapple pin grenades...
9百万枚佩里针式手雷弹
and 1.4 million lightweight...
还有140万轻型...
spigot-launching, anti-tank rocket projectors.
管式反坦克火箭发射装置.
Food production is also up...
食品产量也增长了...
-How's the Newspeak Committee? -Working overtime.
-新说法(Newspeak)委员会那里怎么样了? -没日没夜的工作.
...butter, 2 percent, milk, 6 percent.
...黄油, 2%, 牛奶, 6%.
Plusbig waste is in adjectives.
谈到浪费问题永远都说不完.
Plusbig problem is timing the language to scientific advance.
现在面临巨大的问题是 科技的专业术语的制定和更新.
It's a beautiful thing, the destruction of words.
销毁一些字也是一件很美好的事.
You won't have seen the Dictionary, 10th edition yet, Smith?
你还看过第十版的字典吧,史密斯?
It's that thick.
有这么厚的一本.
The 11th edition will be that thick.
第11版的会有这样厚.
So the Revolution will be complete when the language is perfect.
所以当这门语言完美无缺的时 候,革命也就成功了.
The secret's to move from translation, to direct thought, to automatic response.
这里的秘诀是要把这门语言转变成为 人的直接思维,人的自主本能的反应.
No need for self-discipline. Language coming from here, not from here.
不必自我自缚.语言是直接从你 的喉咙说出来的,是不用经过大脑 修饰一番的.
Excuse me for intruding.
打扰一下.
You're saying that we'll be rid of the last vestiges of Goldsteinism...
你是说我们将会摆脱戈德斯坦主义 的最后的残余势力束缚吗...
when the language has been cleaned.
当这门语言已经变得很好的时候.
-I couldn't agree with you more, brother. -Absolutely.
-我不能赞同你这点,兄弟. -当然.
Praise be to our leader and the Party workers!
歌颂我们的领袖和党的工人们!
Other munitions production figures are as follows.
其它军需品生产的数字如下.
70, 000 M-20 tank destroyers...
70,000辆M-20坦克...
with 76-mm cannon.
装配76毫米火炮.
Smith. Syme.
史密斯.希米.
It's encouraging to think that by 2050...
如果到2050年,还去想那的话 可真是使人感到激动人心.
not a single person will be able to have a conversation like this.
有谁还能活到那一天?
Except the proles?
除了下一代的子孙后代.
The proletariat don't count. They're animals.
这些工人阶级不能包含其中. 他们只是些动物.
See the hanging?
看绞刑了吗?
Missed it, myself.
我自己把这错过了.
Bloody committees.
血腥的委员会.
35,000 Black Eagle 500 cc motorbicycles.
35,000辆黑鹰500cc摩托车.
Doubleplus good, this.
这个,好极了.
You know, I don't think there's a single piece of meat in this stew.
你知道,我不信一点肉都没有.
Looks like meat. Tastes like meat.
看起来像肉,尝起来也像.
It isn't meat at all.
但这根本就不是肉.
Doubleplus good.
味道好极了.
Not like it, Smith?
不喜欢吃吗,史密斯?
Yes, it's too rich for me.
是的,我不习惯吃太营养的东西.
Do you mind if l....
如果我想...你不会介意吧?
Brothers and sisters, the battle for production has been won.
兄弟姐妹们, 产品大战已经取的了胜利.
Completed returns show that the standard of living...
丰厚的回报在生活标准上 得到了体现...
has risen by no less than 20 percent over the last year.
比去年至少有了20%的增长.
All over Oceania there've been spontaneous demonstrations of Party workers...
整个大洋洲的党工人们 都沉浸在...
voicing their gratitude and joy!
极力地表达他们的感激之情 和无限的喜悦.
In honor of this massive overfulfillment of the ninth three-year plan...
为了庆祝这个超额完成的 第九个三年计划...
it's been announced that chocolate ration is to be increased to 25 grams per week!
特此公告: 巧克力的配额将增长到每周25克.
"If there is hope...
如果还有希望...
"it lies in the proles.
也只会在我们的后代.
"If they could become conscious of their own strength...
如果他们对自己的力量还有 所知觉的话...
"they would have no need to conspire.
他们就不需要搞什么阴谋.
"History does not matter to them.
历史是不会记载他们的.
"It was three years ago...
三年前...
"on a dark evening.
一个漆黑的夜晚.
"Easy to slip the patrols.
很容易就把巡逻队给甩开了.
"And I'd gone into the proletarian areas.
然后我就来到了贫民区.
"There was no one else in the street, and no telescreens.
那时街上没有其他人 而且也没有荧光屏,
"She said, '$2. '
"她说,'2美元.'
"So I went with her.
然后我就跟着她走.
"She had a young face...
她有一张娃娃脸...
"painted very thick.
"化着很浓的装.
"It was really the paint that appealed to me...
"吸引我的正是那抹着的粉装...
"the whiteness of it, like a mask...
"很白,就像带着个面具似的...
"and the bright red lips. "
"还有那鲜红的嘴唇. "
Come on.
来啊.
"There were no preliminaries.
"根本就没有性行为前的情热动作.
"Standing there, with the scent of dead insects and cheap perfume...
站在那儿,鼻子里充满了死昆虫 和廉价香水的气味...
"I went ahead and did it, just the same. "
"我靠上前去就和她发生了 关系,和往常一样."
Rutherford unperson.
卢瑟福,被遗忘的人.
Substitute Ogilvy.
替代欧格威.
Ogilvy bio, details as follows:
欧格威个人简历, 详细资料如下:
"War hero.
"战争英雄.
"Recently killed, Malabar Front.
"最近被杀,马拉巴尔近海前线.
"Today awarded posthumous Order of Conspicuous Merit, Second Class."
"今天被授予具有显赫功绩的烈士 勋章,二等功."
I accuse myself of sabotage...
我对自己犯下的破坏活动罪 进行自责...
embezzlement of Party funds...
挪用党内基金...
sale of military secrets...
出卖军事机密...
of being in the pay of the Government of Eurasia...
从欧亚大陆政府机构得到钱...
of being a sexual pervert and a thoughtcriminal.
谴责自己作为一个性变态者 和一个思想罪者.
I exploited my trusted position at the Ministry of Peace...
我利用在和平委员会的显赫的职位...
to mislead our allies in Eastasia...
来欺骗我们在东亚的盟友...
and also to corrupt youth by means of seditious literature and drugs.
与此同时,我还通过宣传煽动性的 文学和鼓励吸毒来侵蚀年轻一代.
I am guilty on all counts.
我承认我所犯下的罪行.
I stand here...
我站在这儿...
a victim of the influence of....
一种势力的牺牲品...
"Under the spreading chestnut tree...
"在那遮荫的栗子树下...
"I sold you...
"我出卖你...
"you sold me. "
"你出卖我."
And I ask only...
我只是想要...
for you to accept...
你们去接受...
my love of our leader.
我们伟大领袖的真挚之爱.
Can I help you?
有什么需要我帮忙的吗?
Anything special?
有什么特别的吗?
I was here before.
我以前也到过这里.
Razor blades.
剃刀片.
You sold me the notebook.
你卖给我一本笔记本.
Yes.
没错.
Please look around.
那你随便看看吧.
What's this?
这是什么?
It's a beautiful thing.
是个漂亮精致的东西.
Over 100 years old.
有一百多年了.
Cost you $4.
4美元卖给你.
There's another room upstairs that you might like to see.
在楼上还有另外一个房间,也许 正是你想要看的.
But there's not much in it.
但那里面的东西不多...
Just a few things.
只有几样东西.
My woman's dead.
我妻子已经去世了.
I'm just trying to sell the furniture.
我正想卖掉这些家具.
It's a beautiful bed...
这是一张漂亮的床...
if you can get the bugs out of it.
如果你能把床上的虫扫除的话.
Interested in old prints at all?
对古画很感兴趣吗?
The frame's fixed to the wall, but I daresay I could unscrew it.
画的框架已经被嵌到墙上了.但 我觉得我还是可以把它取出来的.
How did this escape?
我怎么对这没有印象呢?
I know what it is.
我知道画的是什么.
It's the museum in the street outside the Palace of Justice.
这是耸立在司法殿外街上 的一座博物馆.
"'Oranges and lemons,' say the bells of St. Clement's."
"'橙子和柠檬,'圣.克莱门的钟说'"
What was that?
那是什么?
Something old.
是些古老的东西.
War is peace!
战争就是和平!
Freedom is slavery!
自由就是奴役!
Ignorance is strength!
愚昧就是力量!
A triumph of willpower over the orgasm.
一种对胜利无限追求的意志 远胜于其他东西.
At a rally of the Anti-Sex League in Victory Square tonight...
今晚在胜利广场反性团的一次集会...
held to celebrate a 50-percent decrease in civil marriages...
庆祝市民结婚率减少了50%...
over 10, 000 Party women took a vow of celibacy...
超过1万名的女党员发誓永不 结婚...
and pledged themselves as vessels for the artificial insemination....
并且誓言将会接受人工受孕...
"I hate her.
"我讨厌她.
"I should kill her before she denounces me.
"在她公然谴责我之前, 我得杀掉她.
"I have disliked her from the first moment of seeing her. "
"在我看到她的一瞬间,我就不喜欢她了. "
Sector 43...
第43区...
929 male...
929名男性...
753 female.
753名女性.
Sector 44...
第44区...
437 male...
437名男性...
609 female.
609名女性.
Sector 45...
第45区...
222 male...
222 名男性...
220 female.
220 名女性.
Sector 46....
第46区....
-Are you hurt? -It's nothing.
-你还没事吧? -没什么.
It's my arm.
是我的肩膀伤了.
I'll be all right in a second.
我过一会儿就没事了.
Brother, could you....
兄弟,你能....
Are you all right?
你真的没事吗?
It's nothing.
没事.
I only gave my wrist a bit of a bang.
我只是把我的手关节弄伤了.
Thank you, brother.
谢谢你,兄弟.
Who is she?
她是谁?
All I know is that she works in the corner section...
我只知道她在拐角的那个区工作...
probably on the proletarian novel-writing machines.
或许是贫民阶层的文字人员.
Mrs. Parsons? A spanner?
帕森斯太太? 扳手?
Under the sink, beside you.
哦,在水槽下面, 就在你的旁边.
Thank you, brother.
谢谢你,兄弟.
I wouldn't have had to bother you, but my husband's out late.
我不得不麻烦你, 因为我丈夫出去很晚才回来.
Committees.
委员会.
You know what us Parsons are like.
你知道我们家帕森斯像什么.
You're a thoughtcriminal.
你有思想罪.
They haven't been out much.
他们经常呆在家里.
Thank you, brother.
谢谢你,兄弟.
Attention! Your attention, please!
注意! 请大家注意!
A newsflash has this moment arrived from the Malabar Front.
来自马拉巴尔海岸前线的简报:
The forces of Oceania in South India have won a glorious victory.
大洋洲的军队在南印度取得巨大的胜利.
I am authorized to say that the war against Eurasia...
我郑重声明：这场与欧亚大陆 的战争...
is within measurable distance of its end.
这场战争已经离结束不远了.
40, 000 Eurasian soldiers have been killed or captured.
已经有四万欧亚大陆士兵阵亡或被俘.
Can you hear me?
你能听到我说话吗?
Yes.
可以.
Do you have an ex-London permit?
你有出入伦敦的通行证吗？
Can you get Sunday afternoon off?
你星期天下午可以出去吗？
Yes.
可以.
Take this.
拿好这个.
It's quite precise. I rely on you to destroy it.
它是非常精确的. 全靠你了.
Are you sure you can come?
你确信你能去吗?
Yes.
是的.
On your own, brother?
就你一个人吗,兄弟?
No, I'm joining the Vic Mans community hiking group.
不是,我是和维克希曼社区的 徒步旅行社一起的.
I was held up on urgent Minrec business.
我刚才由于紧急的冥列克事务 给耽误了.
Sing to the bravest on the sturdy fortress
歌唱奋斗在坚固要塞的勇士.
Sing to the soldiers on the battlefields
歌唱在战场上英勇杀敌的战士.
Sing to the airmen in the burning azure
歌唱在火热天空上拼搏的空军.
Sing to the farmers' rising yields
歌唱田野上的累累硕果.
We are the children, builders of the future
我们是祖国的花朵, 祖国未来的希望.
And we the children swear to thee
我们年少的一代向您誓言
Loyal devotion, fearless devotion
忠心,勇敢.
And to die with dignity
不怕牺牲.
Sing to the faithful....
歌唱忠诚的革命者...
A daring and resourceful maneuver...
一个大胆的,深谋的机动战...
under the personal direction of B.B. himself...
在老大哥的亲自指引下...
ensuring the total annihilation of the Eurasian heavy-armored divisions....
完全歼灭了欧亚大陆 的重型装甲部队...
Look.
看.
It's a dream.
这是个梦.
I want you.
我想要你...
Not here.
不在这里.
Come back to the woods, it's safer.
回到树林里去，那儿较安全点.
Have you done this before?
你以前做过吗?
Of course.
当然.
Hundreds of times.
几百次.
-With Party members? -Yes.
-和党成员吗? -是的.
Inner Party members?
内部党成员?
Not with those bastards. Though there's plenty who would.
不是和那些混蛋. 虽然有很多人都这样做.
Look, I hate purity.
我讨厌纯洁！
I hate goodness.
我讨厌善良.
I don't want virtue to exist anywhere.
我不喜欢到那里都要 遵守伦理道德!
I want everyone corrupt.
我要每个人都腐落.
I ought to suit you, then.
那么,我就是你喜欢的类型.
I'm corrupt to the core.
我是很腐落的.
Do you like doing this?
你喜欢这样做吗？
I don't mean just me.
我不喜欢只是满足了我...
I adore it.
我喜欢做.
Winston?
温斯顿?
We shall meet in the place where there is no darkness.
我们要在一个没有黑暗的地方见面.
Adult literacy amongst the proletariat has risen by 56 percent.
成人文学在贫民阶层中 已经增长了56%.
The proletarian infant mortality rate has dropped by 12 percent.
贫民阶层婴儿死亡率已经下降了12%.
Incidences of leukemia, tuberculosis, and meningitis have dropped considerably.
白血病，肺结核，脑膜炎的发病率 也有了较大幅度的下降.
Improved diet has been responsible for a dramatic decrease in rickets.
改善了的饮食也使得软骨病的 发病率有了明显的下降.
Eye diseases show a steep drop.
眼部疾病率也急剧下降.
So, too, do deaths from pneumonia and smallpox.
因天花和肺炎而死亡的数量也在减少.
The improvement in sewerage and drainage systems...
排水,排污系统上的改进...
has resulted in better health, overall.
使得整的健康指数呈现好的趋势.
State rodent operatives report a 50-percent reduction...
国家嚼齿动物中心公布了一篇关于
in the number of vermin in the central proletarian zones.
在中间贫民区寄生虫数量减少了一半的报道.
I just want to finish by saying a few words...
我想用几句话来结束今天的讲话...
about the impact of this imminent neurological breakthrough.
关于未来神经学研究上的突破 所带来的影响.
When the orgasm has been finally eradicated...
当引起人高潮的神经最终被消除的时候...
the last remaining obstacle to the psychological acceptance...
那仅存的阻碍人们接受英格梭克(Ingsoc)理论的...
of the principles of lngsoc, as applied to artsem, will be overcome.
心理障碍也会最终被克服.人工 受精心理障碍也一样.
In other words, the unorthodox tendencies towards ownlife...
换句话说,对我们生命上的异教 医学观念...
which constantly threaten the natural erosion of the family unit...
这种观念无时无刻不在对家庭单位 的新陈代谢功能构成威胁...
will no longer have the biological support of the organism.
将不再得到对生物体生物学上的支持.
As we all know, the biological and social stimulation of the family leads to...
正如我们所知道的那样,一个家庭 生物上的和群居上的演变会引起...
private reflection, outside Party needs...
个人的不同反应,这反应并不是党需要的.
and to the establishment of unorthodox loyalties...
并且导致异教信仰的出现...
which can only lead to thoughtcrime.
这只会给我们带来思想罪的广泛存在.
The introduction of artsem, combined with the neutralization of the orgasm...
人工受精的引入和神经高潮的消除...
will effectively render obsolete the family...
将会有效地改变现有的固定的陈旧的家庭形态...
until it becomes impossible to conceptualize.
直到家庭结构的形成.
Thank you.
谢谢.
Excuse me, brother.
对不起,兄弟.
You dropped your ink pencil.
你的墨笔掉了.
Thank you, sister.
谢谢,妹妹.
A pincer movement has developed...
一种钳形运动已经研发成功...
involving the floating fortresses of the Eurasian 17th Fleet...
主要针对欧亚大陆的第十七舰队的浮动防御要塞...
Not much.
没有什么东西了.
Not much left at all, these days.
在这样的日子里,你怎还能奢望能有什么东西呢?
Walls.
只有墙.
Police don't like us much.
警察是不怎么喜欢我们的.
That room...
那个房间...
how much?
多少钱?
$4 a week.
一星期4美元.
Traitor!
叛徒!
Traitor! Criminal!
叛徒!罪犯!
Big, Big, Big....
大,大,大...(向着老大哥图象)
A vast military buildup of armored divisions...
一次大规模的装甲部队,导弹部队和 浮动要塞的军事集结...
missiles and floating fortresses, accompanied by a fourfold increase...
同时携带了数量四倍于平常的...
in the number of radio-controlled rocket bombs...
无线电遥控的火箭弹...
directed at the most densely populated areas of Airstrip One....
目标指向飞机场一号人群最密集的地域...
It is folly...
这真的有点荒唐...
as though deliberately, we move one step nearer the grave.
好像我们在故意地一步又一步走近坟墓.
I can't understand why she accepted the idea...
我不知道为什么她会接受这样的一个主意...
she, who is so careful.
她,是很小心谨慎的.
Hello.
你好.
Let me show you what I've brought.
给你看看我都带了写什么.
Look.
看.
What is it?
这是什么?
Real sugar.
真正的糖.
Not saccharin.
不是糖精.
And I've got a loaf of bread, proper white bread...
而且我还带了一大条面包,上等的白面包...
and jam.
还有果酱.
A real tin of milk.
一罐新鲜的牛奶.
Look.
看.
Coffee.
是咖啡.
Real coffee.
100%纯咖啡.
Inner Party. Half a kilo.
内部党.半斤.
How did you manage to get ahold of all this?
你是怎么拿得到这些东西的?
There's nothing those bastards don't have.
那些混蛋什么都有.
Aren't you pleased?
你不高兴吗?
Yes.
怎么会呢?
Of course.
当然高兴.
Real tea.
真正的茶叶.
There's been a lot of tea about lately.
最近那儿有很多茶叶.
They've captured lndia or something.
他们已经占领了印度或者别的什么地方.
I want you.
我想要你.
I want you, too.
我也一样.
Wait.
等一下.
Turn around, and don't look until I tell you.
转过身去,我不叫你不许回头.
Listen to that.
听.
How can she make a song written by a machine sound so beautiful?
她怎么能使一台机器写的歌听起来那么好听?
You can turn around now.
现在可以转身了.
-l.... -Winston....
-我.... -温斯顿....
Do you like me?
喜欢我吗?
More than ever.
非常喜欢.
Was there ever a time when this seemed ordinary?
什么时候这些看起来才很普通?
Attention! Your attention, please!
注意!请注意!
A vast military buildup has been reported in the Sahara Desert...
现在报道一个在撒哈拉沙漠的 大规模的军事结集.
sectors 17 and 18 of the war zone.
在17和18战区.
14 heavy-tank divisions....
十四个重型坦克师......
"There is truth, and there is untruth. "
"世上有真言,也有假语"
...have been sighted proceeding in convoy in a northerly direction....
...已经向北方挺进.
"Freedom...
"自由...
"is the freedom to say two plus two equals four.
"是这样的一种自由, 像可以说出2加2等于4.
"If that is granted...
"如果真可以拥有这样的自由的话...
"all else follows. "
"自由就会遍布世界."
That is the end of the announcement.
报道到此结束.
We'll rehab the war from a neutral zone, remaking dust in interstate plusplan levels.
我们将从中间地带重燃战火, 重新发行洲通用货币.
Intend ego 1980 level in dust output by 48 percent.
要比1980年增加42%的货币输出.
Stop, end emission.
停,结束传送.
Re: Times, 31-10-81.
回答:时报,31-10-81.
Brother Tillotson wins Mini chess. Request photo. File follows.
泰搂特森兄弟在微型国际象棋中获胜. 请求照片.档案随送.
Attention. Your attention, please.
注意.请注意.
Will all Outer Party members of Ways and Means Committees...
请参谋委员会的所有外部党成员...
please attend their local community centers for discussions and....
到当地的社区中心参加讨论...
"Under the spreading chestnut tree...
"在遮阴栗树下面...
"I sold you, you sold me. "
"我出卖了你,你出卖了我."
The meetings begin at 20: 00 hours.
会议在20:00开始
Smith?
史密斯?
I've been reading your Newspeak articles in The Times.
我一直阅读你在时报上发表的新说法(Newspeak)文章.
Yes.
噢.
You write very elegantly. That is not my own opinion.
你写得非常优美. 但可不仅仅是我的看法.
I was recently talking to a friend of yours, who is an expert.
我最近和你的一个朋友聊过,他是一位专家.
His name has slipped my memory for a moment.
我一下子记不起他的名字.
What I wanted to say was, that there were one or two unwords, only very recent.
我想要说的是,近来有一两个新词.
Have you seen the 10th edition of the Newspeak Dictionary?
你看了第10版的新说法(Newspeak)字典吗?
No, we're still using the 9th edition at Minrec.
没有,我们在冥列克还用第9版。
A few advance copies have been segregated. I have one myself.
一些提前出版的已经被收起来了, 我自己有一本.
You might be interested.
你可能对这有兴趣.
Yes.
是的.
There are some plus skillful new developments.
有了一些技巧上的新发展.
Let me give you my address.
我给你留下我的地址.
I'm usually at home in the evenings.
晚上我一般都在家.
If not, my servant will give you the dictionary.
如果我不在家,仆人会给你词典的.
14,000 Victory Vampires...
14000门英格梭克(Ingsoc)胜利型大炮...
6, 700 Ingsoc cadets...
6700名英格梭克(Ingsoc)军官学校学生...
4,600 Ingsoc sea cadets...
4600名英格梭克(Ingsoc)海军军官学校学生...
12,300 Porteous piloted missiles...
12,300枚波蒂厄斯机载导弹...
31,000 Victory fighter bombers...
31,000架胜利号战斗轰炸机.
23,000 Big Brother heavy bombers.
23,000老大哥重型轰炸机.
"It has happened at last.
"这一切终于发生了.
"The call has come.
"我等待的那一刻来临了.
"It seems that all my life...
"这好像就是我这一生...
"I've been waiting for it. "
"一直都在等待的时刻."
...is to be named after Sub-lieutenant Ogilvy...
...以潜艇上尉欧格威命名...
hero of the State of Oceania...
大洋洲的英雄...
recently awarded, posthumously, the Order of Conspicuous Gallantry...
近来被追记,授予英勇烈士勋章...
for his action in the recent glorious victory...
以肯定他在最近取的巨大胜利中的 英勇表现...
over the forces of Eastasia on the Malabar Front, in South India.
这场胜利是在南印度马拉巴尔海岸 前线与欧亚大陆军队的战争中取得的。
Half the water's boiled away.
水已经烧开了一半.
What does the clock say?
几点了?
It says 21 :00 hours.
21:00点了.
What time do they cut the light in your flats?
你的房间几点断电?
23:30.
23:30.
At the hostel it's 23:00.
在旅店是23:00.
What is it?
这是什么?
I don't know.
我不知道.
A little chunk of history that they've forgotten to alter.
一小块他们忘记去修改的历史.
Message from 100 years ago.
100年前留下的消息.
"'Oranges and lemons,' say the bells of St. Clement's."
"'橙子和柠檬,'圣.克莱门的钟说"
"'You owe me three farthings,' say the bells of St. Martin's."
"'你欠我3便士,'圣.马丁的钟说"
Who taught you that? What is it?
谁教会你的这些?这是什么?
I don't know. I just know it.
我也不知道,我只知道它是什么.
You know, the only thing to do...
你知道,现在唯一要做的事是...
is to walk out of here before it's too late...
要尽快地走出这里,在危险到来之前.
and never see one another again.
并且彼此不要再会面.
Yes.
好的.
Our luck can't last.
我们的运气不会再持续下去了.
You're young...
你很年轻...
you look normal, you're innocent.
你看起来很正常,你是清白的.
You keep clear of people like me, and you might stay alive.
你应该远离象我这样的人， 你还可能活下来。
What you do, I do.
你做什么,我就做什么.
I've thought it out.
我已经考虑好了.
I'm good at staying alive.
我是很善于生存的.
When shall we meet again?
什么时候我们还会见面?
Not for several weeks. It's not safe.
最近几周不行,不安全.
Give me half an hour.
给我半个小时.
I love you.
我爱你.
Julia....
朱丽亚....
Do you think the Resistance is real?
你认为抵抗是真的吗?
No.
不.
None of it's real.
没有真的.
Steamer! Dead overhead! Get down!
蒸气飞机！危险! 趴下!
...round the clock, plus a 153 sets in eyes top a P.M.A. Willmer.
...昼夜不停,加上153套要留意的东西 让人有些力不从心了.
"Oceania is at war with Eastasia.
"大洋洲正在与东亚交战.
"Oceania has always been at war with Eastasia.
"大洋洲一直都在和东亚交战.
"Eurasia is our ally. Eurasia has always been our ally.
欧亚大陆是我们的同盟. 欧亚大陆一直都是我们的同盟.
"Everything fades into mist.
"一切都烟消云散.
"The past is erased, the erasure forgotten.
"过去的被擦去,擦掉的又被忘记.
"A lie becomes truth and then becomes a lie again. "
"谎言成为真理,然后又重新变成谎言."
What is it?
你干嘛了?
I dreamt...
我梦到...
about my mother.
我的妈妈.
What, darling?
发生什么了,亲爱的?
It was during the wars...
这是在战争其间...
before the Party.
在加入党以前.
Winston!
温斯顿!
I couldn't help myself.
我控制不住自己.
I knew what I had done...
我知道自己做了什么...
and I couldn't help myself.
我无法控制住自己.
When I went back, hours later...
几小时后,当我回去时...
my mother and sister were gone.
我妈妈和妹妹都不见了.
I never saw them again.
从此我没有再见过她们.
So it's not just staying alive.
所以,人不仅仅要活着.
It's staying human that's important.
更重要的是要有人性.
What counts...
也就是说,让我铭记在心的是...
is that we don't betray each other.
我们彼此不能背叛对方.
If you mean confessing, we're bound to do that.
如果你指的是忏悔的话, 我们肯定会这样做.
Everybody does.
每个人都会这样去做.
You can't help it.
你也是无法控制住自己的.
I don't mean confessing.
我不是指忏悔.
Confessing isn't betrayal.
忏悔不是背叛.
I mean feelings.
我指的是情感.
If they can make me change my feelings...
如果他们能使得我改变我的情感...
they can stop me from loving you.
他们就可以阻止我们的爱情.
That will be real betrayal.
那才是真正的背叛.
They can't do that.
他们是不能做的.
It's the one thing they can't do.
这是一件他们所办不到的事情.
They can torture you...
他们可以折磨你...
and make you say anything.
并让你说出任何东西.
But they can't make you believe it.
但他们不能使你信仰它.
They can't get inside you.
他们夺走不了你的灵魂.
They can't get to your heart.
他们控制不了你的内心世界.
I'm going to see O'Brien.
我将要和欧尼尔.布莱恩见面.
I know.
我知道.
Outer Party Member 53922...
外部党员53922号来自...
Hicks, Minirec, Proletarian Affairs Section.
希克,米尼列克室,贫民阶层事务部.
Outer Party Member 22315...
外部党员22315号...
Howard, Miniprod, Hospital Section.
霍华德,米尼劳德室,医院部.
Outer Party Member 947743...
外部党员947743号...
Bolgar, Minitrue, Records Section.
鲍歌,米尼楚尔室,档案部.
Outer Party Member 5739, Brady, Minitrue, Records Section.
外部党员53922号...
Outer Party Member 984213...
外面的984213号党员...
Devereux, Minitrue, Records Section.
德福罗,米尼楚尔室,档案部.
Outer Party member 9106...
外部党员9106号...
Dawes, Minitrue, Porno Section.
道斯,米尼楚尔室,成人书刊部.
Outer Party Member 38091...
外部党员38091号...
Ware, Minitrue, Porno Section.
威尔,米尼楚尔室,成人书刊部.
Outer Party Member 1 1792...
外部党员11792号...
Bigland, Minitrue, News Section.
比格列德,米尼楚尔室,新闻部.
"ltems one, comma, five, comma, seven, approved fullwise. Stop.
"第一项,逗号,五,逗号,七, 批准.完毕.
"Suggestion contained item six doubleplus ridiculous verging crimethink...
"建议包括了法则六超乎寻常的 边缘犯罪思想...
"Cancel, stop. End message."
"取消,停止.结束通话."
Outer Party Member 4392...
外部党员4392号...
Rosenblum, Miniprod, Light Industry Section.
罗森布伦,米尼劳德室,轻工业部.
Outer Party Member 66755...
外部党员66755号...
Davis, Miniprod, Women's Section.
戴维斯,米尼劳德室,妇女联合会.
That concludes the list of known agents of Goldstein...
那包括了一份戈德斯坦著名的 特务的名单...
actively engaged in the latest conspiracy....
积极地参与了最近的密谋...
Not much of this gets to the Outer Party, I'm afraid.
恐怕这样的见面很少能发生在外部党员身上,是吧.
To our leader.
为了我们的领袖.
...that our eternal allies in Eurasia are turning against us.
...我们在欧亚大陆的长久的盟友正在 把枪口转向我们.
More nests of conspirators and saboteurs have been uncovered...
越来越多的反叛分子和从事破坏活动分子 的窝点被发现...
and further arrests are expected shortly.
不久后将会采取进一步的逮捕行动.
You can....
你可以....
Yes. We are allowed that privilege.
是的,我们有这种特权.
Some more of this?
再来点吗?
It's called wine.
这叫做葡萄酒.
There are thoughtcriminals who maintain the Resistance is not real.
有些犯有思想罪者声张反抗因子 并不是真的存在...
Believe me, Winston...
请相信我,温斯顿.
it is very real.
这的确是真的.
Perhaps you are not familiar with how it operates.
也许你并不怎么熟悉它是如何运做的.
I'm attentive to the news.
我只是留心那些新闻.
Indeed.
事实上.
Perhaps you imagine a huge network of conspirators...
也许你可以设想存在着这样的 一个反叛罪犯的大集团...
prepared to commit any atrocity to demoralize...
已经准备好要采取任何行动...
and weaken the order of our society.
给我们的社会制造动乱.
The reality is infinitely more subtle.
这种行为肯定被掩盖得很好.
If Goldstein himself...
如果戈德斯坦本人
fell into the hands of the Thought Police, he could not give them a list of his agents.
落到政治警察手里, 他可能交不出他的特务名单.
Such a list does not exist.
这样的一个名单并不存在.
They're not an organization in the sense we know.
据我们所知,并没有所谓的这样一个组织.
Nothing holds it together but an idea.
维系他们在一起的只有这样一种思想， 并没有一个具体的东西.
There is no possibility of change in their lifetime.
在他们一生中都不可能有改变.
In the face of the Thought Police...
在思想警察的追捕下...
they cannot act collectively.
他们不能光明正大地集体协作.
Individually, they cheat...
只能秘密地,单独行动,进行欺骗...
forge, blackmail, corrupt children...
伪造,勒索和侵蚀儿童...
spread disease and prostitution...
传播疾病和嫖娼...
in the name of spreading knowledge from generation to generation.
以传授知识的名义一代又一代地 进行着...
Until...
直到...
in a thousand years....
一千年后....
You may find this of interest.
你也许会发现它的重要性.
Thank you.
谢谢你.
...address a rally in Victory Square at 21:30 hours.
...今晚9:30在胜利广场举行集会.
That is the end of the announcement.
本次公告完毕.
Goodbye, brother.
兄弟,再见.
They have attacked an unarmed village with rocket bombs...
他们用火箭弹袭击了一个非武装的村庄.
and murdered 4, 000 defenseless, innocent...
并且杀害了4000名没有武装的,无辜的
and peaceful citizens of Oceania.
并且爱好和平的大洋洲的居民.
This is no longer war.
这已经不再是一场战争.
This is cold-blooded murder.
而是一场杀人不眨眼的屠杀.
Until now, the war has been conducted with honor...
到现在,这场战争在尊严...
and bravery...
勇敢...
with the ideals of truth and justice, in the best traditions of mankind...
真实和正义完美结合体--人类最美好的一面 的精神下进行着.
until this moment.
直到这个时刻.
Brothers and sisters...
兄弟姐妹们...
the endless catalogue of bestial atrocities...
那种无休止的残忍的暴行...
which will inevitably ensue from this appalling act...
这种暴行会不可避免地带来这一 令人发指的行为...
must, can, and will be terminated.
必须,能够,也一定会被终止.
The forces of darkness and treasonable maggots...
那些黑暗势力的军队 和与之贯通一气的蛆虫们...
who collaborate with them, must, can, and will...
必须,能够,也将会...
be wiped from the face of the earth.
永远从地球上消失.
We must crush them.
我们必须将他们制服.
We must smash them.
我们必须将他们碾成粉碎.
We must stamp them out.
我们必须将他们根除.
We, the people of Oceania...
我们,大洋洲的人民...
... will not rest until a final victory has been achieved.
...将不会停息我们的斗争直到 赢得最后的胜利.
Death to the eternal enemy of Oceania.
让永远与大洋洲为敌的去死吧!
Death!
去死吧!
Brothers and sisters...
兄弟姐妹们...
one week from now...
从现在开始的一周里...
in this very square...
就在这个广场上...
we shall, as a demonstration of our resolve...
我们将要,为了表示我们的决心...
as a sure sign to those who attempt to threaten...
为了向那些还在试图威胁 我们党和国家的人...
our Party and our State...
发出警告的信号...
we shall execute publicly...
我们将公开处死...
the same number of Eastasian prisoners...
一定数量的东亚囚犯...
by hanging, drawing and quartering.
通过执行绞刑,车裂和剐刑.
Big, Big, Big....
大,大,大....(向着老大哥图象)
"In accordance to the principles of Doublethink...
"根据思想矛盾的原理...
"it does not matter if the war is not real...
"即使战争不是真的,也无关紧要...
"or when it is, that victory is not possible.
"或者即使是真的时候，那种胜利是不可能的.
"The war is not meant to be won. It is meant to be continuous.
"战争本来就没有输赢， 只会不断的持续.
"The essential act of modern warfare...
"现代战争的最精华的部分...
"is the destruction of the produce of human labor.
"就是对人类劳动成果的破坏.
"A hierarchical society is only possible on the basis of poverty and ignorance.
一个存在着等级的社会只可能 建立在贫穷与无知之上.
"ln principle, the war effort is always planned...
"根据常规,战争的目的往往是...
"to keep society on the brink of starvation.
"使得社会处于饥饿的边沿.
"The war is waged by the ruling group against its own subjects.
"战争是为统治集团实现其目的而服务的.
"And its object is not victory over Eurasia or Eastasia...
"它的目的不是为了在和欧亚大陆或 东亚交战中取得胜利...
"but to keep the very structure of society intact. "
"而是为了保护社会的完整结构. "
Julia?
朱丽亚?
Are you awake?
你醒着吗?
There is truth, and there is untruth.
世界上存在着真言,也有假语.
To be in a minority of one doesn't make you mad.
成为其中少数的一个 是不会使你发疯的.
Julia, my love...
朱丽亚,亲爱的...
I understand how.
我知道怎样.
I don't understand why.
但我却不知道为什么.
I'm hungry.
我饿了.
Let's make some more coffee.
让我们弄些咖啡.
The water's cold.
水是冷的.
There's no oil in it.
里面没有煤油了.
That's strange. I thought it was full.
真是奇怪,我还以为它是满的.
They say that time heals all things
他们说时间可以治愈任何东西.
They say you can always forget
他们说你可以总是忘记
But the smiles and the tears
但是留在历史年轮上的
across the years
微笑和眼泪
they twist my heartstrings yet.
还纠缠在我的心弦上.
She's beautiful.
她真漂亮.
She's a meter across the hips. Easily.
她的臀宽都有一米宽了.很容易就看出来.
It's her style of beauty.
这才是她的美丽之处.
The future is hers.
未来是属于她的.
We are the dead.
我们都会死去.
You are the dead.
你也会死去.
Remain exactly where you are.
呆在原地不动.
Make no move until you are ordered.
没有得到命令前,不要乱动.
Now they can see us.
现在他们能看到我们了.
Now we can see you.
现在我们可以看到你们了.
Clasp your hands behind your heads.
把手紧抱在你们的头后.
Stand out in the middle of the room. Stand back-to-back.
背靠背站到房的中间.
Do not touch one another.
不要互相接触.
The house is surrounded.
房间被包围了.
I suppose we may as well say goodbye.
我想我们也应该说声永别了
You may as well say goodbye. While we're on the subject...
你们也许可以说永别了.但我们 才刚刚开始.
"Here comes a candle to light you to bed.
"这里有一支蜡烛照引着你们到床边.
"Here comes a chopper to chop off your head. "
"这里就会有一个侩子手把你们的头砍掉. "
Pick that up.
把它捡起来.
Thought Police.
是思想警察.
6079 Smith. Open your eyes.
6079号,史密斯，睁开眼睛
Parsons.
帕森斯.
Keep away from me, Smith.
离我远点,史密斯.
I'm an agent of Goldstein.
我是戈德斯坦手下的特务.
I didn't know it myself.
我自己以前竟然也不知道.
Thoughtcrime is so insidious.
思想罪是防不胜防的.
It just creeps up on you.
它就是要染上你.
My daughter found it out.
我的女儿先发现了它的存在.
Very proud of her.
很为她感到自豪.
Very grateful I've been discovered before it's too late.
令人高兴的是,我是在变得无可救药 之前就被发现了.
They won't shoot me, will they, Smith?
他们是不会杀了我,是吗,史密斯?
I know I could be very useful in a labor camp.
我觉得在劳动营里我的作用是很大的.
Room 101.
101房间
No.
不要.
Please, you don't have to take me there.
请不要,你们不必把我带到那里去.
Why?
为什麽呢?
There's nothing I won't confess.
我已经够坦白的了.
Nothing.
已经没有要坦白的.
I've told you everything already.
我已经把所有的事情都告诉你们了.
What is it you want me to know?
你们到底想要我知道些什么?
Take him instead of me.
不要带我,带他,带他.
He's the thoughtcriminal. It's him you want.
他才是真的思想犯, 你们想要的是他.
They got you, too.
他们也把你抓了.
They got me a long time ago.
他们早都抓过我了.
You knew this would happen, Winston.
你以前也知道终有这么一天的,温斯顿.
Don't deceive yourself. You've always known it.
不要再欺骗你自己. 你已经知道这是什么了.
The photos of you and the girl will be recycled for proletarian use.
你和那个女孩的照片将被用为宣传 贫民阶级性质的教育上.
Do you know where you are, Winston?
温斯顿,你知道你在哪儿吗?
I don't know.
我不知道.
I can guess.
我可以猜测.
In the Ministry of Love.
在爱的国度.
Do you know how long you've been here?
你知道你来这儿多久了吗?
No.
不知道.
Weeks?
几星期?
Months?
几个月?
Do you know why you're here?
你知道你为什么会在这儿吗?
Shall I tell you why we brought you here?
要我告诉你为什么我们要带你到这里吗?
To cure you.
为了给你治疗伤痕.
To make you sane.
为了使你恢复健康.
That was 40.
刚才是40.
You can see that the numbers on this dial run up to 100.
你会看到在转盘上的数字将会拨到100.
Will you please remember that, during our conversation?
在谈话过程中,请你记住这一点.
I have it in my power to inflict pain on you at any time...
我有权在任何时候给你痛苦...
and in whatever degree I choose.
我也有权决定我所要增加痛苦的程度.
You know perfectly well what is the matter with you, Winston.
你很清醒地知道你自己有什么问题,温斯顿.
You've known it for years, though you've fought against the knowledge.
尽管你一直都在与那理论做斗争, 但你已经意识到它有好几年了.
You are mentally deranged.
你在精神上已经近乎疯狂.
You suffer from a defective memory.
你忍受着对自己记忆的折磨的痛苦.
You never tried to cure yourself of it, because you did not choose to.
你从未想过治愈自己,因为你没有选择这样做.
It was a small effort of will, which you were not ready to make.
这只不过是在意志的作的一个小小的努力 但你却丝毫不想去做.
For example...
举个例子...
which power is Oceania at war with?
大洋洲在与那个强国交战?
Eastasia.
东亚.
Oceania is at war with Eastasia.
大洋洲在与东亚交战.
Good.
很好.
And Oceania has always been at war with Eastasia, has it not?
大洋洲一直都在与东亚作战,是不是?
Tell me what you think you remember.
告诉我你觉得你记起什么了.
I remember...
我记得...
that until only a week before I was arrested...
直到我被捕前的一周
we weren't at war with Eastasia at all.
我们才和东亚交战.
It was Eurasia.
以前是欧亚大陆.
That lasted four years, I think.
我觉得这场战争持续了四年.
Another example.
举另一个例子.
A serious delusion.
一个严重的错觉.
Photographs about which you've had hallucinations...
你已经对一些照片产生幻觉...
which you believed you held in your hand.
使得你确信那些照片已经那在你的手中.
They never existed.
事实上它们并不存在.
Say what you were about to say, Winston.
告诉我这时你想要说的,温斯顿
They exist...
它们存在...
in memory.
我的记忆中.
I remember.
我记得.
You remember.
你记得.
I do not remember.
我并不记得.
Only the disciplined mind can see reality, Winston.
只有经过严格训练的大脑才辨得出,温斯顿.
It needs an act of self-destruction...
要做到这一点需要一种自我否定精神.
an effort of the will.
一种意志上的努力.
Do you remember writing in your diary:
你记得在日记中你所写的:
"Freedom is the freedom to say two plus two equals four"?
"自由是这样的一种自由, 像可以说出2加2等于4"?
Yes.
记得.
How many fingers am I holding up?
我现在举起几根手指?
Four.
四根.
And if the Party says there are not four, but five, then how many?
如果党说这不是四而是五根,那又将是多少?
Five.
五根.
No.
不对.
That's no use. You're lying.
那是没用的,你在说谎.
How many fingers, please?
请问有几根?
Four. What else could I say?
四根,我还能说几根呢?
Five, or anything you like. Will you please stop it?
五,或者你喜欢要我说什么都行. 请你不要折腾我了好吗?
Stop the pain.
不要再折磨我了.
How can I help it?
我该怎样做呢?
How can I help what I see in front of my eyes?
我怎么才能确定我眼前看到的东西呢?
Two and two makes four.
二加二等于四.
Sometimes, Winston.
这是有时是而已,温斯顿.
Sometimes they are five, sometimes they are three.
有时是它可以是五, 有时是它可以是三.
Sometimes they are all of them at once.
有时它又全部都是.
Neither the past, nor the present, nor the future...
过去,现在,将来...
exists in its own right.
都不会以他们的正确形式出现.
Reality is in the human mind...
事实存在于整个人类的思想中...
not in the individual mind...
而不在人类个体的思想中...
which makes mistakes and soon perishes...
这种思想常常会犯错误,然后会很快腐烂...
but in the mind of the Party...
而是在党思想里...
which is collective and immortal.
党的思想是集体的和不朽的.
-Again. -No.
-再说一遍. -不行.
How many fingers, Winston?
有多少根，温斯顿?
Four.
四根.
Four, I suppose there are four.
四根,我觉得应该是四根.
I tried to see five.
我试着去看到五根.
I wish I could.
我希望我也能做到.
Which do you wish?
你希望什么呢?
To persuade me that you can see five, or really to see them?
想去说服我你能看到了五根 或者你真的看到了五根吗?
Really to see them.
真的看到五根.
Again.
再来.
How many, Winston?
有多少根,温斯顿?
I don't know.
我...我...我不知道.
Better.
这次好点.
No one escapes, Winston. There are no martyrs here.
没有人能回避的,温斯顿. 这里没有烈士这一说法.
All the confessions made here are true.
在这里所做的任何坦白都是真的.
We do not destroy the heretic because he resists us.
我们不会迫害异教徒 因为他抵制我们.
As long as he resists us, we never destroy him.
只要他还在抵制我们, 我们决不伤害他.
We make him one of ourselves before we kill him.
在我们杀他之前,我们要把他归顺 成为当中的一员.
We make his brain perfect before we blow it out.
在我们把他的大脑砍下来之前,我们 要使得他的大脑变的灵活.
And then...
然后...
when there is nothing left but sorrow and love of Big Brother...
当什么都没有的时候,只留下了对 老大哥的爱与恨...
we shall lift you clean out of history.
我们会将你从历史的每一页中抹掉.
We shall turn you into gas and pour you into the stratosphere.
我们会把你变成气体, 然后倾倒到大气层的顶部.
Nothing will remain of you.
你一根骨头都不会留下.
Not a name in a register.
在注册本中没有你的名字.
Not a memory in a living brain.
在每个活生生的大脑里没有记忆你的存在.
You will be annihilated in the past, as well as in the future.
你将在过去,未来世界中消失.
Three thousand.
三千.
This time it won't hurt you.
这次不会伤到你了.
Before we bring this session to an end...
在我们结束这次交谈之前...
I want you to ask me your questions.
我想要你问我点问题.
I want you to clear your mind.
我想要你使得你的大脑变得清醒起来.
Julia.
朱丽娅
She betrayed you, Winston...
她出卖你,温斯顿...
immediately, unreservedly.
很快地,毫不保留地.
All her rebellion, deceit, folly, dirty-mindedness...
她所有的反叛,欺诈,荒唐,肮脏的思想
has been turned out of her.
都已经从她的大脑里消失.
Does Big Brother exist?
老大哥真的存在吗?
Of course.
当然存在.
The same way as me?
像我这样的存在吗?
You do not exist.
你不存在.
You've not asked me the question that is uppermost in your mind.
你还没有问我你最想问的问题.
You know what is in Room 101.
你知道101房间里有些什么.
Everyone knows what's in Room 101.
每个人都知道101房间里有些什么.
Now...
现在...
fix your eyes on mine.
把你的眼睛盯着我看.
What country is Oceania at war with?
大洋洲在和那个国家交战?
I don't remember.
我不记得了.
Oceania is at war with Eastasia.
大洋洲在和东亚交战.
Do you remember that now?
你现在记起这些了吗?
Yes.
是的.
How many fingers am I holding up?
几个指头?
Five.
五根.
You see, at least, that it is possible.
你看,至少这也是一种可能性.
You've understood the reality of the past...
你已经理解了过去的真实存在...
and of the present.
和现在的.
Now for the future.
现在问未来的.
A question:
一个问题:
"How does one man assert power over another?"
一个人怎样可以从另外一个人手中夺到权力?
By making him suffer.
折磨他.
Exactly. Obedience is not enough.
非常正确,顺从是不够的.
Power is inflicting pain and humiliation. Otherwise, you cannot be sure.
权力是制造痛苦和耻辱的原因. 否则,你不能肯定.
Power is tearing human minds apart...
权力正在将人类的思想撕成粉碎...
and putting them together again in new shapes of your own choosing.
然后又将它们重新组合成 你想要的原形.
Power is not a means, it is an end.
权力不是手段,而是一个端点.
In our world, there will only be triumph and self-abasement.
在我们的世界,只能存在胜利和自卑.
Everything else, we shall destroy.
所有其他的我们都要摧毁掉.
The past is forbidden. Why?
过去是被禁止的,为什么?
Because when we can cut man from his own past...
因为当我们将一个人从他的过去 分离开的时候...
then we can cut him from his family, his children, other men.
我们可以把他从他的家庭, 孩子和其他人分离开.
There is no loyalty, except loyalty to the Party.
除了对党之外,这儿没有忠诚.
There is no love, except love of Big Brother.
除了对老大哥之外,这儿也没有爱.
All competing pleasures, we will destroy.
所有与之相对的感情,我们都要将之摧毁.
If you want a vision of the future, imagine...
如果你得到一个未来的幻影,想象...
a boot stamping on a human face forever.
一只靴子永远踏在一个人的脸上的情景
You are thinking that my face is old and tired...
你在想我的脸是如此皱的而且又累倦...
that while I talk of power...
以至于当我谈论到权力的时候...
I'm unable to prevent the decay of my own body.
我竟不能阻止我自己身体的衰老.
But the individual is only a cell.
但个体仅仅是一个细胞.
And the weariness of the cell is the vigor of the organism.
而细胞的衰亡却是生物体充满活力的标志.
-You'll fail. -Why?
-你会失败. -为什么?
It's impossible.
这是不可能的.
Hatred, the fear of life.
憎恨,是惧怕生活的源泉.
Why is hate less vital than love?
为什么恨与爱相比没有这么重要呢?
I don't know.
我不知道.
But somehow you'll fail.
但是,无论如何你都会失败.
Something will defeat you.
总有一些东西会将你打败.
Life will defeat you.
生活将会把你打败.
We control life at all levels.
我们控制着生活的方方面面.
We create human nature.
我们创造了人类的本性.
Men are infinitely malleable.
人类是永远繁殖下去的.
Or perhaps you've returned to your old idea that the proletarians will arise.
或者你也许已经回到了你以前的 旧观念:贫民阶级会最终崛起.
Put it out of your mind.
不要再把它留在你的头脑里.
They are helpless animals.
他们只是些没有用的动物.
Humanity is the body.
人性才是人的身体所在.
I don't care. In the end, they'll beat you.
我才不管什么.最后,他们最终会将你打败.
Sooner or later, they'll tear you to pieces.
迟早,他们会将你撕成粉碎.
On what evidence?
有什么根据吗?
Goldstein's book.
戈德斯坦的书.
I wrote it. Or, at least, I collaborated in writing it.
那是我写的.或者可以说,我是 和别人一起写的.
No book is individually produced, as you know.
正如你所知道的那样,没有一本书是 单纯靠一个的的智慧写出来的.
I just believe it.
这我相信.
I know you'll fail.
我知道你终将失败.
Something in this world...
在这个世界的某些东西会...
some spirit you will never overcome....
某种精神你永远征服不了....
What is it, this principle?
那是什么呢,这个原理吗?
I don't know.
我不知道.
The spirit of man.
人类的精神.
And do you consider yourself a man?
那么你认为你自己是一个真正的人吗?
Yes.
是的.
If you are a man, you're the last man.
就算你是这样的一个人,你也是最后一个.
Your kind is extinct.
你的人性已经不复存在了.
We are the inheritors.
我们才是人性的继承者.
Do you understand that you are alone?
你还没有意识到你是孤零的一个人吗?
You are outside history.
你已经走在了历史的外面.
You unexist.
你是不存在的.
Get up.
起来.
Come here.
到这边来.
Look at you.
看看你自己.
You're rotting away.
你已经颓废了.
That is the last man.
这就是最后的人种.
If you are human, that is humanity.
如果你是人类,那就是所谓的人性.
It will not last forever.
这不会永远持续下去的.
You can escape from it whenever you choose.
无论什么时候你都可以摆脱开它,
Everything depends on you.
一切都取决于你.
You did it.
是你造成的.
You reduced me to this.
是你把我逼成这样的.
No, Winston.
你错了,温斯顿.
You reduced yourself to it.
是你把你自己逼成这样的.
When will you shoot me?
你打算什么时候杀我?
Might take a long time.
也许要过好长一段时间.
But don't give up hope.
但不要放弃希望.
Everyone is cured sooner or later.
每个人都是可以治愈的,只是时间问题罢了.
And in the end...
然后到最后...
we shall shoot you.
我们就会把你杀了.
The law of gravity is nonsense.
地心引力定律只不过是谎言.
No such law exists.
根本没有这样的原理存在.
If I think I float...
如果我想我在漂浮...
and you think I float...
而你也在想我在漂浮...
then it happens.
那么我就是在漂浮.
I love you.
我爱你.
You have the strength, Winston. You have the whole Party.
温斯顿,你有这样的一种力量. 你可以拥有整个党.
You are the Party.
你就是党.
You're one of us, one of the chosen.
我是我们中的一员,注定是.
I love you.
我爱你.
I love you, too.
我也爱你.
Julia, my love.
朱丽亚,我的宝贝.
Get up.
起来.
Stand up straighter.
站直点.
Look me in the face.
看着我的脸.
Tell me, Winston, and remember, no lies.
告诉我,温斯顿,好好想想,不要说谎.
What are your true feelings towards Big Brother?
你对老大哥的真实感受是什么?
-I hate him. -You must love him.
-我恨他. -你必须爱他.
It's not enough to obey him.
仅仅服从他是不够的.
You must love him.
你必须爱他.
Room 101.
带到101房间.
You asked me once, Winston, what was in Room 101.
温斯顿,你以前曾经问过我,到底 101房间里有什么.
I told you that you knew, already. Everyone knows.
我告诉过你你早已经知道了。 每个人都知道。
The thing that is in Room 101...
101房间有...
is the worst thing in the world.
这个世界上最令人恐怖的东西.
It goes beyond fear of pain or death.
甚至超过了你对痛苦或死亡的恐惧.
It is unendurable, and it varies from individual to individual.
这是不可忍受的. 对它的恐惧也会因人而异.
It may be burial alive or castration...
这有可能会是活埋或阉割...
or many other things.
或者别的其他东西.
In your case, it is rats.
而你要面临是,老鼠.
No.
不要.
Please. What do you want me to do?
请不要.你想让我做什么?
You will do what is required of you.
你会做你需要做的.
What? What is it?
什么?这到底是什么?
How can I do it if I don't know what it is?
我都不知道这是什么?我又怎样做呢?
In the proletarian areas, they will attack a baby...
在贫民区里, 他们会对一个孩子袭击...
and within five minutes, strip it to the bone.
在数分钟内,就只剩下骨头.
They also attack the sick and dying.
他们也会对病人和垂危的人袭击
They show astonishing intelligence in knowing when a human being is helpless.
当一个人束手无助的时候, 他们会表现令人惊异的才能.
Please.
求求你.
The mask fits over your head, leaving no exit.
这个面具恰好盖住你的头, 你是逃不过了.
I press the first lever...
我打开第一层闸...
and the rats move into the front compartment.
老鼠就会跑到前面的厢子.
I press the second, and the door of the cage will slide up.
我打开第二层闸,笼子的门就会滑开.
These starving brutes will shoot at you like bullets.
这些早都等吃的畜生会像子弹一样 向你射去.
Have you ever seen a rat leap through the air?
你以前有看过一只老鼠在空中飞跃吗?
They will leap onto your face and bore straight into it.
他们会直飞跃到你的脸上 然后直钻进你的身体里.
Sometimes they attack the eyes first.
有时它们会先袭击你的眼睛.
Sometimes they burrow through the cheeks and devour the tongue.
有时它们会挖穿你的脸颊, 然后吞食你的舌头.
Tell me. What do you want?
告诉我,你想要什么?
No, please.
求求你,不要.
I love you.
我爱你.
Do it to her! Do it to Julia!
让老鼠咬她!咬她!
I don't care what you do to her, but do it to her!
我不在意你对她怎样,但也要让 老鼠咬她!
Tear her my face off! Do it to Julia, not to me!
把她的恋撕破! 让老鼠咬她,不要这样对我!
Do it to Julia!
让老鼠咬她!
Not me!
不是我!
A vast military buildup has been reported in the Sahara Desert...
据报告在撒哈拉大沙漠的一次大规模的军事大集结...
in Sectors 17 and 18 of the war zones.
在17和18分战区.
That is the end of the announcement.
通告到此结束.
Brother.
兄弟.
On the house.
免费的.
Thank you for coming.
谢谢你能来.
You are warned to stand by for an important announcement at 15:30.
请大家注意在15:30收听一则重要的通告.
This is news of the gravest national consequence...
这是一则关系国家存亡悠关的新闻...
concerning the war with Eurasia.
关于与欧亚大陆之间的战争.
15:30.
记得是15:30.
Are you worried about the African front?
你对非洲前线战局有忧虑吗？
The news is disquieting in the extreme. I've been worrying about it all day.
这则消息真的是让人担心死了. 我整天都在想着它.
It's not just a question of losing Africa.
这不仅仅是丢掉非洲的问题.
For the first time, the territory of Oceania itself is threatened by invasion.
大洋洲的本国领土有史以来第一次受到入侵.
It's inconceivable.
这真是令人难以想象.
It must have been possible to outflank them in some way.
一定还有办法从侧面包围他们.
I have an instinct.
我有直觉.
There's bad news on the way.
呆会儿肯定是坏消息.
I told them all about you.
我把你的所有的一切都告诉他们了.
I'm only thankful they got me before it was too late.
我只是很感激他们在我无法挽救 以前救了我.
Yes, I told them about you, too.
是的,我也把你的所有的一切都告诉他们.
Thoughtcrime...
思想罪...
sexcrime, all your treachery.
sex　crime, all your treachery. 性犯罪等,所有你的叛逆行为．
I have a meeting to go to.
我有一个会议要参加.
We must meet again.
我们还会再见一次面的.
Yes.
是的.
I accuse myself of the following crimes:
我对我以下的罪行感到自责:
I have seduced Party members of both sexes...
我引诱党成员,包括男性和女性.
I've been to the proletarian areas...
我曾到过贫民区...
I deliberately contracted syphilis in order to spread the disease...
我故意染上梅毒是为了想传播这种疾病．．．
to my wife and other Party members.
给我的妻子和其他党员.
Together with other agents, I have counterfeited banknotes...
和其他特务一起,我伪造了钞票...
wrecked industrial machinery, polluted the water supply...
破坏工业设备,污染水供给...
guided Eurasian rocket bombs to targets on Airstrip One...
为欧亚大陆提供情报信息,使他们的 火箭弹能袭击到飞机场一号地域...
by means of coded radio signals.
通过无线电信号传达.
I stand here, a victim of the influence of Emmanuel Goldstein.
今天我在这儿,作为一个以马利.戈德斯坦 势力的受害者.
Guilty on all counts.
我有罪.
I'm glad I was caught. I was mentally deranged.
我很高兴我被抓住了. 因为以前我在心灵上已经近乎疯狂.
Now I am cured.
现在,我已经伤愈了.
I ask only for you to accept my love of our leader.
我只希望你们能热情拥抱我们领袖的爱.
I ask only to be shot while my mind is still clean.
我只求,在我还清醒的时候,一枪把我打死.
A glorious victory!
一场伟大的胜利!
A vast, strategic maneuver to outflank...
一次大规模的,有策略的机动侧翼围剿...
the Eurasian Forces on the African front has been successful.
欧亚大陆的非洲军队已经进展的十分顺利.
Perfectly coordinated, it has resulted in the utter rout of the Eurasian Army.
由于各队的完美协作,已经使得欧亚大陆的军队 在战场上全面溃退.
There have been nearly a million prisoners. It has been an utter rout.
已经有大约一百万的敌人沦为囚犯. 这是一个全然的大溃退.
Waiter?
服务员?
This immense victory brings the war within measurable distance of its end.
这个伟大的胜利使得我们离最终胜利 的日子指数可待。
Wonderful news.
好消息.
I love you.
我爱你...